Have you ever heard about that
the cliff of a snow mountain
once fascinated numerous people?
Legend has it that,
there were treasures at the peak
but also there was a bottomless chasm hidden over there.
The smart, the fool
and the kind people,
all are familiar to you.
On the mountainside, on the cliff,
on the cloud,
and in the human world,
snowflakes are drifting profusely and disorderly.
Joy of Life Season 1
Episode 26
Dad, you want to see me.
You're back.
Come and take a seat.
The negotiation
in Court of State Ceremonials is over.
Be cautious at the Hall tomorrow.
You mean
the banquet tomorrow night?
What's wrong?
It's known to the world that
literary giants are all in Beiqi.
In earlier years,
scholars actually found it an honor
to pass the imperial examinations in Beiqi.
Though things are better these years,
when it comes to scholars,
Nanqing is no match to Beiqi.
Now the Nanqing literary circles
have anchored their hopes on you.
Me?
The literary circles?
That poem with the line
“A thousand miles from home, I'm grieved at
autumn's plight” which you wrote a few days ago
is rated as the No.1 Current Seven-character Poem
by scholars of Nanqing.
Many say in private that
accomplished at such a young age,
you can be better than Zhuang Mohan in future.
I just wrote one poem.
They are too hasty in drawing the conclusion.
One poem is not much,
but we've longed for a talented scholar
for so long.
We may even fight a losing battle.
Who will lose?
You, of course.
So tomorrow night,
everyone will watch me
meeting the literary giant
Zhuang Mohan.
You don't need to be amazing.
Just play it safe.
That's enough.
Will you go tomorrow night?
The banquet tomorrow
is especially set for Court of State Ceremonials
and Board of Rites.
I'm the Assistant Minister of Ministry of Revenue.
Why would I go?
Don't worry.
Just a little advice.
Respected as Zhuang Mohan is,
why would he actually make things difficult
for a young man like you?
Fan Xian will also attend the banquet tomorrow night.
Master Zhuang, please ruin his name.
You've hung up a red lantern.
Uncle, for all these years,
I've been wondering
whether you can see or not.
How come you know
I hang up a lantern?
And you even know the color.
It's hard for me to explain.
I can know everything.
But I don't see with eyes.
You see with your heart.
I don't know how to put it.
Uncle.
I find you mysterious all the time.
If anyone dares to piss you off,
he's definitely dice with death.
Take a seat. Take a seat. Take a seat.
Let's get down to business.
Tomorrow night,
the imperial family will hold a banquet at
the Hall of Prayer for Good Harvest.
The Hall of Prayer for Good Harvest?
How is Wang Qinian involved?
(Qinian sounds like Prayer for Good Harvest in Chinese)
Who?
Wang Qinian.
Uncle,
besides being mysterious,
how come your thoughts
are so hard to follow recently?
Thoughts?
I don't think the Hall of Prayer for Good Harvest
has anything to do with Wang Qinian.
Fine.
Let's get down to business.
The banquet tomorrow is mainly for
the celebration of finishing the war against Beiqi.
It's kind of a big event.
Aren't you going to ask me
why I ask you over?
Aren't you going to tell me if I don't ask?
You've made a point.
Fine.
After the banquet tomorrow night,
we'll break into the imperial harem.
Are you sure?
Everyone will relax
after a great event.
OK, the plan remains unchanged.
I will lure away Hong Sixiang,
and you should sneak into the Empress Dowager's palace
to find the key.
There's one last problem.
I don't know
where the Empress Dowager keeps the key.
It might take time to find it.
There's a secret compartment
on the bed board under her pillow.
All her important things are kept there.
How do you know that?
Your mom searched it before.
Why did my mom
search her secret compartment?
The old lady has lived in widowhood for so many years.
Though she looks serious,
I wonder whether she keeps
love letters in private or not.
Those are the words said by your mom back then.
So she searched the Empress Dowager's
secret compartment only for gossiping!
I've no idea
what gossiping implies,
but yes, you're right.
Didn't she get caught?
I kept watch for her.
Why are you laughing?
Words can't express
my feelings right now.
What feelings?
Just forget it.
Anyway, back then,
my mom had solved
the biggest problem for me.
Now,
as long as I know where the key is,
I feel quite sure of getting it out.
If we take the key,
the old lady might notice.
We'd better put in a fake one.
Without seeing the real key,
how could you make a fake one in advance?
I've got an idea.
Good.
Wait for me here tomorrow night.
Someone's here.
I asked him over.
Seriously?
Your Excellency.
Come in.
It's quite late now.
Do you have anything for me?
I have a question for you.
Please go ahead.
Do you have anything to do with the
Hall of Prayer for Good Harvest?
I suppose not.
I think so.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Take a seat.
Your Excellency, thank you.
I might as well stand.
Your Excellency,
I heard that by deterring the Beiqi mission
in the Court of State Ceremonials,
you've made great contributions to Nanqing.
=Ten taels of silver=
I will attend the banquet tomorrow night.
Your Excellency, charismatic and vigorous as you are,
you'll definitely be promoted in the near future.
Is this for me?
Yes.
Thank you, Your Excellency.
Your Excellency,
next time you grant me a reward,
please grant me bank notes instead.
They are easier to hide.
I want to break into the imperial harem at night.
Your Excellency,
pardon, please?
I said I want to break into the imperial harem at night
and sneak into the Empress Dowager's palace
to steal a key.
Of course,
for fear the old lady might notice,
I have to make a fake key overnight
to replace the real one.
That's my plan.
Are you kidding me?
Not really.
Are you serious?
Yes.
It's a deadly sin which could implicate your family.
I suppose it is.
Then why do you
tell me about it?
I just told you
I have to make a fake key
overnight.
I have to find the best locksmith in the capital city.
Since I'm not familiar with the capital city,
I need someone with connections.
That's you.
If I'm involved,
I will also commit a deadly sin.
You just find me a locksmith
to make a key.
You know nothing else.
Right!
Then you should only ask me
to find a locksmith.
Right? Why tell me
the whole plan?
I also want to tell you less,
but I can't.
You have to wait for me
outside the imperial palace tomorrow.
Your Excellency!
Aren't you afraid that I might tell on you?
Do you really want to
trust me
with your life?
Of course I do.
You're a wise man.
You should know that
you only need to take a little risk by helping me,
but you'll get yourself killed if you dare betray me.
What do you mean?
You know how Chen Pingping
treats me.
The Head treats you like his son.
So this is the case.
If I tell on you
and get you killed,
the Head will definitely
cut me into pieces.
You're really wise.
Then why don't you ask the Head
to do you the favor.
It's inconvenient for big potatoes
to do such things.
What can I say?
The choice is yours.
I know a good locksmith.
Good. Ask him to wait for me tomorrow night.
OK.
From tonight on,
I'll raise your salary by another ten taels of silver.
This is something that might get my entire family killed.
You only add ten taels of silver?!
Don't you think it's too little?
So you don't want it?
I want it.
Give me bank notes instead next time.
What time is it now?
It's about 1:00 p.m.
Is the Hall of Prayer for Good Harvest ready?
Yes, they started decorating
early this morning.
Find me a place for the night banquet.
It's only held for Court of State Ceremonials
and Board of Rites.
It's no big deal.
Just do it.
Yes.
I can't wait.
I've asked.
As to the night banquet in the
Hall of Prayer for Good Harvest,
guests can take seats at about 5:00 p.m.
Your Highness, if you eat too much now,
you won't feel like eating
in the banquet.
On such banquets,
there will be a lot of drinking and praises.
How could I fill my belly?
That's right.
Such banquets
are merely a formality.
Your Highness really don't
have to go.
Fan Xian completed his first task successfully.
I certainly should
congratulate him in person.
Hasn't Fan Xian taken the side of
the Crown Prince?
Who told you so?
If not, why would the Crown Prince
send him to negotiate with the Beiqi mission?
Man like Fan Xian
won't follow the Crown Prince willingly.
I've only met Fan Xian a few times,
but I find him a bosom friend.
Just like me, Fan Xian won't feel content
to occupy a position below others.
How long has His Highness stood there?
About an hour.
His Highness is afraid to form folds on his gown.
What time is it now?
Your Highness, it's about 5:00 p.m.
Let's go to the Hall of Prayer for Good Harvest.
Yes.
Master Zhuang, the carriage is ready.
We're ready to go.
Let me take this for you.
Your Excellency, I've talked with the locksmith.
Good. Let's go drinking.
Your Excellency Fan!
Your Excellency Xin!
What a coincidence!
Indeed!
Your Excellency Fan,
why not wear your robe?
It's just a meal.
I'm not some high-ranking official.
Well then. I'll have
more drinks with you later.
Your Excellencies, regular examination.
No edged tools
can be taken inside.
Who would bring edged tools to a banquet?
Your Excellency Fan, listen!
The ritual music
is prepared by the Board of Rites.
Can I bring needles in?
Steel needles. About this long.
No.
Wait a moment.
That's all.
Your Excellency Xin, let's get inside.
I'm cautious because I was assassinated before.
Yes, you should be.
It's right to be cautious.
Can I bring in poisons?
Poisons?
No! No! No!
Fan Xian.
Your Highness.
What's going on?
Don't touch it.
These are poisons made by myself.
I'm not allowed to bring them inside.
You're really Fei Jie's student.
Can they kill?
Of course.
Give me a bag.
No.
Why?
If anything happens to His Majesty
and the Crown Prince,
I won't be able to justify myself.
Right. Just forget it.
Fan Xian, you've rendered meritorious services this time.
You'll definitely have a bright future. Congratulations!
Thank you, Your Highness.
We can see each other more.
I might be able to help in the imperial court.
I'm so flattered.
Your Highness.
You're from Court of State
Ceremonials. Your name is Wang...
Xin!
Xin... Xin... Xin...
Xin Qiwu.
I remember you're a follower of the Crown Prince.
We're all couriers! We're all couriers!
If you feel dissatisfied
following the Crown Prince,
you can follow me instead.
There should be none left.
Now there's none left.
Don't touch them.
I don't have the antidotes
for some poisons.
Your Excellency Xin.
What are you thinking?
In your opinion,
why does the Second Prince come to the banquet?
To draw talents like Your Excellency Xin
over to his side
of course.
Your Excellency Fan, you're making fun of me again.
It's obvious that the Second
Prince was trying to win you over.
How could it be me?
Your Highness! Please believe me!
I'm definitely loyal
to Your Highness.
I will never follow others.
Your Highness!
Your Highness, I can prove that.
Just now, the Second Prince
did try to win him over,
but loyal as His Excellency Xin is,
he didn't take the offer.
Right! Right! Right!
Your Excellency Fan, thank you for telling the truth.
You're welcome.
Don't worry. His Highness is open-minded.
Yes! Yes! Yes!
Your Excellency Fan, something's not right.
The Second Prince actually
said those words to win you over.
How come you become the one
to clear my name instead?
It's the same.
Your Excellency, it's not!
The Princess Royal is also here.
=Guo Baokun, son of Guo Youzhi,
Minister of the Board of Rites=
Brat, do you dare
=Guo Baokun, son of Guo Youzhi,
Minister of the Board of Rites=
Brat, do you dare
to see me?
Who are you?
Unbelievable!
You're the one who beat me on the street.
Now you actually pretend
you don't know me!
Young Master Guo.
Long time no see!
Your wounds are almost healed.
Good for you.
How dare you forget me!
Mind your words! Mind your words!
You sound like a whining woman.
You villain!
I'll never forget
what you've done!
You sound more like it.
Why are you here? Why is he here?
He. He. He.
I am the Imperial Compiler.
My father is the Minister of the Board of Rites.
Why can't I be here?
You can! You can!
The dishes will be served soon.
-Mr. Guo, please take your seat. -Don't be smug.
Fan Xian, let me tell you.
Today, right here,
I'll watch you hit rock bottom
and ruin your name
with my own eyes.
Nonsense!
Father.
What's the occasion?
Go back to your seat!
Yes.
=Guo Youzhi, Minister of the Board of Rites=
My son is so rude.
Your Excellency Fan, please forgive him.
Who are you?
This is Guo Youzhi,
Minister of the Board of Rites.
Minister, it's you.
Your Excellency, don't worry.
Your son is mischievous and lovely.
I'm not angry at all.
Well. Well. Well.
Come on! OK! OK!
Stop looking around.
Our seats are over there.
Come on! This way, please!
Let's sit here.
Come on! Have a seat!
Have a seat!
Your Excellency Fan, have a seat!
Your Excellency Fan,
Guo Baokun is also a follower of the Crown Prince.
You'd better make peace.
I'm fine with that.
Just look at him.
Your problem will be solved gradually.
Your Excellency! Your Excellency!
Did you really beat him?
How could that be?
By reading the books of sages since childhood,
I've always been denying self and returning to propriety.
How could I beat others?
But you killed a martial arts master
from Beiqi on the street a few days ago.
Nice wine.
Right. Right. Nice. Nice.
Xin,
there are two seats left.
For whom?
Probably for the two masters
from Dongyi Town and Beiqi.
Beiqi has sent the literary giant Zhuang Mohan.
Who has Dongyi Town sent?
As for Dongyi Town...
=Yun Zhilan, first apprentice of Great Master Si Gujian=
Your Excellency Fan! Your Excellency Fan!
Are you OK?
How can he carry a sword into the imperial palace?
Apprentices of Si Gujian
never leave their swords behind.
His Majesty has made an exception for them.
Apprentice of Si Gujian?
He's the first apprentice of
Great Master Si Gujian,
whose name is Yun Zhilan.
Yun Zhilan?
Those two female assassins
you killed on the street
were his apprentices.
The Dongyi Town mission
is also sent here to settle that.
Does he sell wine?
I've never heard of that.
Your Excellency, why do you ask?
It sounds like a wine's name.
Really?
Your Excellency Fan,
the Princess Royal asks you over
to tell you something.
Come closer.
These days,
I've been waiting for you to kill me.
How come there are no surprises?
Your Highness, take it easy.
You'll be surprised at any time.
If you pledge allegiance to me,
I'll let Wan'er marry you.
I'll let you have the financial power of the Neiku.
And I'll give you more whatever you want.
What if I want to kick you out of
the capital city?
A great wish.
You should definitely try.
I won't fail Your Highness for sure!
Fan Xian and Auntie
are talking happily.
I wonder what they're talking about.
It's none of my business.
Your Highness wants to
win Fan Xian over, right?
Let's make a bet on
who will get Fan Xian in the end.
What shall we bet?
Life.
It seems I've made
an improper joke.
Your Highness, please forgive me!
OK.
Zhuang Mohan is here.
=Zhuang Mohan, Beiqi Litterateur=
You've never met Master Zhuang, right?
It might be fate
for Beiqi to have
such a literary giant.
After explaining classic texts and
annotating articles for decades,
he's got many works to his credit.
In some way,
he's even more powerful than an emperor.
Carrying the literary inheritance all by himself,
doesn't he find it burdensome?
If the scholars heard what you just said,
you would be accused of disrespect of the saint.
Why would I admit
I said those words?
I heard some people
have anchored their hopes on you,
expecting you to become
a literary giant in future.
Your Highness won't hope so for sure!
Well, since Master Zhuang is here,
the banquet should start soon.
Go back to your seat.
I'll excuse myself.
I've given you the chance,
but you've thrown it away.
Here arrives His Majesty!
This way! This way! This way!
May Your Majesty live ten thousand years!
All rise.
Thank you, Your Majesty!
His Majesty has arrived at the
Hall of Prayer for Good Harvest.
Have you checked
all the maidservants, eunuchs and imperial guards
on shift tonight?
Yes, I have.
All of them have a clean family background.
No one is suspicious.
Among those who entered the Hall,
have you found anyone suspicious?
Yes,
Fan Xian is.
According to the Division of Imperial Guards,
he carried a dagger and poisons with him
when he arrived.
What about Zhuang Mohan?
Zhuang Mohan only took inside
a roll of old paper.
My men took the chance to check it.
There was nothing inside.
In my opinion,
Zhuang Mohan doesn't practice
martial arts.
He wouldn't be a problem.
Yun Zhilan went inside with his sword.
Right.
But Yun Zhilan is an apprentice of Si Gujian.
He is not supposed to
know Zhuang Mohan.
If Yun Zhilan tries to
kill His Majesty with his sword,
who can stop him?
Eunuch Hong Sixiang is right outside the Hall.
Serve the dishes.
Eunuch Hong, it's a night owl.
Young Master Guo.
Chief Musician Fan.
Your Excellency Fan, His Majesty is calling you.
Calling me?
What does His Majesty call me?
You're the Chief Musician of
the Court of Imperial Sacrifices.
That's the name of your official position.
Your Majesty.
You've seen me a few times, but you've never knelt down.
I thought you would remain standing this time.
Then I would piss off everyone.
Look at your blurred eyes.
You must have drunk a lot.
Your Majesty.
On such a big occasion,
I can't help feeling nervous.
Yun Zhilan.
Your two apprentices
were killed by him.
I know.
Young as he is,
he's somewhat competent.
He's competent if he can kill me.
The apprentice of Si Gujian
is really proud.
I get that.
Fan Xian.
According to the memorial submitted
by Court of State Ceremonials,
you've done a great job this time.
The war was started because of you,
and it was ended by you.
I don't want to praise you in public.
Come on! Join me for a drink.
Chief Musician Fan, please wait.
Your Majesty, I have something to say.
Go ahead.
Besides being good at martial arts,
Fan Xian is also famous for literary grace.
I'm amazed by his talents
in writing poems.
Recently, I've heard that
when negotiating with Beiqi,
Fan Xian handled it properly without
being too humble or too pushy.
He can be entrusted with important tasks.
Just go straight to the point.
Why not put Fan Xian in charge of
the imperial examinations next spring?
Scholars going down in history
under the supervision of a youth talent,
it might become a much told tale.
Though Fan Xian is known for his poems,
he is inexperienced after all.
Your Majesty.
Though inexperienced,
he is really talented.
I support the suggestion
to put Fan Xian in charge of the imperial
examinations held in spring.
Well...
How could this be?
There're still a few months
before the imperial examinations.
We'll see by then.
Go back to your seats.
Your Majesty.
Is this young man Fan Xian?
Master Zhuang, have you also heard of him?
I've read his poem.
Young as he is,
he's talented in poetry.
Master Zhuang, you should guide and
support the younger generation.
I'm a minister from Beiqi.
I should not interfere with the political affairs of Nanqing.
But the imperial examinations held in spring
are of fundamental importance
to scholars around the world.
You should be cautious
when choosing the man in charge.
Master Zhuang, you're absolutely right.
When it comes to the imperial examinations,
we can't be too cautious.
Master Zhuang, I admire you for being
well versed in the learning of
both ancient and modern times,
but I don't agree with what you just said.
Though I'm a woman
with little knowledge,
I've read the seven-character poem written by Fan Xian.
He's young indeed,
but this poem alone
can show he's really talented.
What you said just now
is secretly against Fan Xian.
Are you afraid that
this young man might surpass you one day
and gain a better reputation than you?
Everyone else present here is either a trustworthy minister
or a learned scholar.
They certainly don't like to argue.
Ignorant as I am,
I'm willing to speak up for
our talent of Nanqing.
Are you referring to that seven-character poem?
Exactly!
Master, have you got any poem
better than that?
Yunrui, mind your manners in the Hall.
Master Zhuang, you're broad-minded.
Please forgive her for being rude.
The wind so swift, the sky so wide, apes wail and cry;
Water so clear and beach so white, birds wheel and fly.
The boundless forest sheds its leaves shower by shower;
The endless river rolls its waves hour after hour.
A thousand miles from home,
I'm grieved at autumn's plight;
Ill now and then for years, alone I'm on this height.
Living in times so hard, at frosted hair I pine;
Cast down by poverty, I have to give up wine.
What a fantastic poem!
I've written poems my whole life,
but none
can match that.
So Master Zhuang,
you admit defeat candidly.
The first four lines are wonderful.
But people all say
the essence of the poem
is the latter four lines.
The latter four lines are absolutely marvelous.
But unfortunately,
they were not written by Mr. Fan.
So Fan Xian copied the poem.
Yes.
I also find it strange.
How could he
be so talented?
Fan Xian,
do you have anything to say?
Master Zhuang can say
whatever he likes.
After all, highly respected as Master Zhuang,
what he says counts even if he has no proof.
Your Majesty,
I can prove that
Fan Xian wrote the poem at the poetry gathering
held in Prince Jing's mansion.
Guo Baokun, the Imperial Compiler
was also there.
He can be a witness.
Is Guo Baokun here?
Yes, Your Majesty.
Did Fan Xian write the poem?
Yes.
In this case,
Master Zhuang is trying to frame Fan Xian up on purpose.
He might be misled by others
to form such a misunderstanding.
What a coincidence!
The latter four lines of the poem
were written by my teacher
when he was visiting Tingzhou.
It should to be a good thing to see
such wonderful lines reappearing in the world.
But Mr. Fan
actually made a name with other's poem.
Is that appropriate?
For scholars, morality is more important than talent.
The first four lines of the poem
are remarkable.
Mr. Fan is definitely talented.
But why does he have to be so greedy
as to make a name
with other's work.
I was hesitant about
telling the truth.
But after careful thinking,
I feel that by telling the truth,
I might help Mr. Fan
correct his mistake.
There's no making without breaking.
He can focus on moral cultivation in future.
Mr. Fan,
I told the truth
because I cherish your talents.
I mean no harm.
Please be introspective.
Fan Xian,
feel free to speak your mind.
Master Zhuang,
is your teacher surnamed Du?
No.
Never mind.
Master Zhuang is known for
respecting teachers and honoring truth,
I suppose he won't use his teacher's reputation
to frame up an innocent man.
But men are hard to predict.
He might feel unhappy
seeing a young man rising to his fame
and make all this up to destroy his future.
Your Highness,
are you suspecting me of framing this young man up
at the cost of my teacher's reputation?
I dare not.
It's just that unlike Beiqi,
Nanqing emphasizes laws.
If you want to accuse someone,
words alone
won't be enough.
Your Highness, you've made a point.
Look, it was written by my teacher
back then.
Could it be
the proof?
The lines are exactly the same.
In the river of history,
time goes round and round.
Memories about the former and present lives
join each other in an endless way.
In the long drunken Milky Way,
one season follows another in a flash,
and the wild geese are flying south.
I just can't give up
to be with you for my whole life.
I have been hovering in the dreams
for hundreds and thousands of times.
I can't even say a word when I watch the flowers falling.
Year after year in the wandering,
I count the remaining years.
Even though we can't meet each other anymore,
even though we have ended up the destiny,
I never feel regretful.
In such a chaotic world,
I still miss you as ever.
I can't fall asleep under the moon.
With a gentle heart,
I cherish our remaining years.
Even though we have to go through
all the hardships along the journey,
you always stay by my side,
watching the falling flowers, speechlessly.
Year after year in the wandering,
I count the remaining years.
Even though we can't meet each other anymore,
even though we end up the destiny,
I never feel regretful.
In such a chaotic world,
I still miss you as ever.
I can't fall asleep under the moon.
With a gentle heart,
I cherish our remaining years.
Even though we have to go through
all the hardships along the journey,
you always stay by my side...